I was dreaming?
It's been a long time since I've had that dream.
Lord Hiraku!
I'm terribly sorry.
I still haven't finished the morning chores...
Don't worry about it. I woke up early today.
So anyways...
I'd really appreciate it if you
stopped calling me "lord".
Very well...
Mayor.
Good morning!
Good morning to you.
I was careless...
So you're working in the kitchen now.
I'll just roast the whole thing.
No, cut him some slack.
Oh?
You're up early today, aren't you?
Yeah, I just woke up a little while ago.
Good morning!
What're you doing here?
I had to talk to Granmary about something
while she was on patrol duty.
Is there a problem?
It's nothing like that.
She reported to me earlier
about something, and...
Is something wrong?
No, it's nothing.
I just had a dream I haven't had in a while.
A dream?
Actually, it's more like
an old memory than a dream.
Back then, I really never could have imagined...
that I'd ever get to live such a dream of a life.
Hiraku Machio.
That's you, isn't it?
Yes.
And, um... you are?
I'm the god who watches over this world.
You're God?
Ah, so I guess that means I finally died.
Indeed.
According to this world's calendar
you've lived 39 years.
And what a cruel life it was.
You were betrayed by others,
and then fell ill with a terminal disease.
That's why I've decided to give you
a chance at a second life.
You can do that?
Of course.
This time shall grant you
a healthy body that won't fall ill.
You see, I consider it a mistake on my part
that you were forced to live
such a cruel existence in the first place.
Your mistake?
I ask that you take this act
as penance for my mistake.
Uh...
I don't really get it, but okay.
Let's make sure to do this right.
Do you have any requests?
I'll let you live your new life
the way you want to.
The way I want to?
I can grant pretty much
any request you have.
In that case...
I've got it!
I want to try my hand at farming!
Farming?
I really enjoyed watching a show about farming
while I was stuck in the hospital bed.
It was a show about idols farming!
In my last life, I had a hard time
getting along with other people,
so I thought it would be nice
if I could live a laid-back life
of farming somewhere
where not many people go.
Is that too much to ask?
No, it's just that farming
isn't part of my jurisdiction.
Your jurisdiction?
But let's give him a call and see.
Ah! Hm? Okay.
It is done.
You'll receive your new life and
a healthy body with which to live it.
In addition, I've received permission
from the god of agriculture
to bestow upon you the power of
the almighty farming tool.
The almighty farming tool?
Now then...
Enjoy your chance at a second life.
My body can move.
It's been a long time
since I've been able to move around.
How many years has it been
since I've been able to stand up?
Having a healthy body is amazing!
Alright, I've come back to life
safe and sound.
It's time to start my second life...
the farming life that I wished for!
So this is where I start?
Let's grasp the situation at hand.
What the heck's goin' on here?
Forest.
Forest as far as the eye can see.
I know I asked for somewhere
that not many people go,
but this almost feels like a place
that people can't reach even if they want to.
Oh well. No use in complaining now.
I need to think about what I can do from here.
I'm dressed like a villager from a video game.
And I get the feeling that
I'm younger than I used to be.
Do I have anything I can actually use?
That's right! The almighty farming tool...
This is it!
Here we go.
This must be magic power or something.
No matter how much I use this hoe,
I don't get tired.
And I can till the hard ground and
cut through tree roots without a problem.
This soil's nice and fluffy.
I'm sure I can grow some great vegetables
in a field I till with this...
Wait a minute.
I need to worry about finding
water and food right now.
Let's search the area.
Ain't there anything around here?
The forest goes on and on.
I tried listening carefully so that I could
hear if any streams were nearby,
but all I could hear was
the rustling of the leaves.
Forget finding edible plants...
I don't even see any grass
growing around here.
Am I playing on the right difficulty setting?
Now that I think about it,
there's a good chance that there could be
dangerous animals around here.
I need to hurry and find somewhere safe.
That's one nice tree.
It'll make a good landmark.
I think I'll set up my base camp here.
Let's gather materials.
Are you making money?
I walked around for a while, but there
don't seem to be any rivers or ponds nearby.
In that case...
I'll dig a well!
Dowsing
A method of finding things
hidden underground based on
the movement of sticks or pendulums.
I bet you're thinking that it's silly to try
to find water underground like this.
But I've heard that people sometimes use
this method to find water pipes. Maybe.
I don't get this at all.
Shovel!
This almighty farming tool
really lives up to its name.
It can turn into all kinds of stuff.
For the record, it can't turn into
complicated machines.
Excavator!
For the record, it can't turn into
complicated machines.
Uh, make something big and awesome!
For the record, it can't turn into
complicated machines.
Uh, make something big and awesome!
Just as I expected!
I don't get tired no matter
how much I dig, just like the hoe!
Now I can dig forever until I hit water!
Am I stuck down here?
I know... I'll dig diagonally!
I only just started digging...
It's my lucky day!
No, this might be another one
of God's blessings.
Now that I've secured my source of water,
it's time to find food.
That was my plan...
but oddly enough, I don't feel hungry at all.
I wonder if this is the power of
the almighty farming tool, too.
It's probably dangerous to go
wandering through the forest again.
Scythe!
Since I'm definitely going to turn this
into my base of operations,
I'll keep working on building it up
with the almighty farming tool.
It'd be nice if I found something to eat
while I was working here...
I don't see anything around here. Oh well.
If I'm going to cultivate the land here,
this tree is going to be
in the way eventually.
It looks like a pretty sturdy tree,
but maybe if I turn the almighty farming tool
into an axe, I can cut it down.
I think the right way is
to start cutting one side,
and then go in from
the other side with the axe.
I did it!
Okay then.
I'll start from this side.
Here we go!
Huh?
I cut it clean in two with one swing...
This almighty farming tool is something else.
Hatchet!
Since I've already cut it down,
I should try to process it down into lumber.
I'll start by cutting off the branches,
then I'll cut the trunk up into logs.
Then I'll strip the bark off.
I'm cutting through the sturdy tree
like it's a block of cheese.
So about this hook-like tool
that I'm using to drag the tree around...
I'm not sure what it's called, but apparently,
I can turn the almighty farming tool
into anything I can imagine.
Now I've got myself some lumber.
Based on the farming sim games
I used to play,
this is about the time I should start
building small hut out of the lumber.
But it's not going to be easy to build
the parts for the walls and roof.
Plus, I don't have any nails or
adhesive to stick them together.
Building a hut from scratch
is pretty tough, isn't it?
Hm...
This pillar I stuck in the ground for fun
is casting a shadow almost like a sun dial...
Oh no!
I was having so much fun
that I lost track of time!
The sun's about to set
and then it's going to be night.
And what happens then?!
It's going to be dark out!
I need some kind of light.
Flashlight! Lamp!
No good. I'll need to start a fire!
Lighter! Matches!
It's no use.
Maybe this has something to do with that
jurisdiction issue God was talking about.
Besides, the thought of turning
the almighty farming tool into a match
only for it to burn away
and be lost forever is scary!
I need something that can create heat
without burning itself away.
I've got it!
Magnifying glass!
It worked!
I can start a fire with this.
Or rather, I could have if it was daytime.
I ended up quickly carving a hole
into the tree's trunk,
so I'd have some kind of shelter.
I thought about digging a hole in the ground,
but the thought of accidentally burying myself
alive scared me so I gave up on the idea.
This chisel is another form of
the almighty farming tool.
It looks like it'll take a lot of trial and error
before I can make furniture or a hut.
I was worried I wouldn't be able
to see when it was dark out,
but I'm surprised at how well
I can still see at nighttime.
Maybe it's because when God granted me
a healthy body, my vision improved as well.
Or maybe...
It's because of those.
The two moons casting light.
Wow...
I really am in another world, aren't I?
Den carved into the tree trunk
Well
Pillar
I did a lot of trial and error trying to
figure out how to work with the lumber,
and before I knew it, morning had come.
It looks like I'll be fine
in terms of having water.
That's right!
I need to do that before I forget!
And now I have a fire going, too.
Heave-ho...
From there, I continued clearing the area
so that I could cultivate the land.
I don't get tired or hungry
while using the almighty farming tool,
but I'm sure that doing this kind of work
is using up some of my body's stamina.
Even specks of dust can pile up
to make mountains.
In other words, I think it's finally time
for me to eat something.
It might be time to change gears
and go look for food somewhere
further away from here.
Wh-what is that thing?!
Well, that was a happy accident.
I had no choice but to kill it.
It had scary fangs and stuff.
All it took was one blow to the neck
with the almighty farming tool's hoe.
I tilled the giant rabbit's head
and turned it into nice a fluffy soil.
Then I turned the almighty farming tool into
a knife and used it to take apart the body.
At least I'll be able to make use of its body
to feed myself. I'm thankful for that.
Grilled rabbit...
It tastes very natural.
Or rather, it tastes gamey and bloody.
Still, I'm grateful that I have
something to eat.
What goes in must also come out.
The next thing I built was a toilet.
The toilet seat was made from a log.
Toilet seat
Below that, I dug a hole.
Gas release
Tank
Toilet seat
Gas release
For removal
Tank
Now I can relax and take care of my business.
I can't relax at all.
I put to use some of the building technology
I developed instead of sleeping last night.
It ended up being better built
than where I slept last night, but...
A toilet that's comfortable to use
is necessary for any sort of civilized lifestyle.
I took a bunch of detours getting here,
but I've finally started cultivating the land.
What should I grow
to help support my life here?
I'll need stuff that preserves well.
Potatoes?
Onions?
Some tomatoes and cucumbers would be nice.
You can eat those as is.
Cabbage and spinach.
Daikon. Napa. Carrots.
Oh, I want to eat some boiled corn, too.
I've realized something here.
Even if I cultivate the land,
I have no seeds or seedlings to plant.
I guess my only option is to head
into the forest to look for something.
I went to bed on a stomach full of rabbit meat
and when I woke up the next morning,
my eyes opened in surprise when they saw this.
Can the plants in this world grow
even if you don't plant their seeds?
Or could this be because of
the almighty farming tool?
There are sprouts popping up in every row.
And it only took one night!
But these sprouts look different
than the plants I'm used to seeing...
Those kind of look like scallions,
but they're bent.
Well, I'm not sure what they are.
But even if I'm not sure what they are,
I know what I have to do!
I need to protect these fields
from those giant rabbits
and any other beasts that live in this forest!
First, I'll build a fence around the perimeter.
Then, I'll dig a ditch around the fence.
I'm still a little worried,
but I feel a lot better having this built.
After a few days, the fence and
the ditch were completed.
During that time, I fed myself with
the meat from another rabbit
I killed when it tried charging into my fields.
I wonder why they always
charge in headfirst like that.
Maybe I'm what they're trying to
attack and eat.
Nature...
If I water them with the watering pot
from the almighty farming tool,
they get bigger every day.
They're growing a lot faster than normal plants.
I'm still not exactly sure what I'm growing,
but I hope it's stuff that I can eat.
If they all turned out to be
decorative plants...
I'm sure that I'd fall to my knees in despair.
A few more days passed.
After all my hard work,
I was able to build a small hut.
I cut grooves into the wood
and stacked them on top of each other.
It's basically a log house.
Part of the way through I wasn't able to lift
the lumber up to the top anymore,
so I dug out the ground a bit
to give myself more vertical space.
For the roof, I used bark from the trees
and held it down with nails I made
from shaved down wood.
If I was in a fairy-tale,
a wolf would be able to huff and puff
and blow this house down,
but I think this is a lot more civilized
than living in a hole I dug into a tree.
I can't wait to see how my crops turn out.
I feel really motivated lately,
and I've been looking forward to each new day.
That was when I started to get into
a routine with my new life here.
Dogs?
They're huge.
They don't seem like
they're going to attack me.
And they look like they're in
pretty rough shape.
Come on.
Perfect timing. I just killed a boar
and didn't know what to do
with all the meat.
It was trying to get over my fence,
so I had no choice but to exterminate it.
One of them has a swollen belly.
I wonder if he was trying to take
the pregnant one somewhere safe
when they were attacked by
some other animal.
This reminds me of when I was a kid
and I wanted to get a dog.
They say that dogs are a farmer's friend.
It'd be nice if they hung around here.
What's wrong?
Is she about to give birth?!
Here? Now?!
What should I do?
How can I help?
Well, it's probably better
than being outside
so I led them into my log house.
How long does it take for dogs to give birth?
Does she need water to drink?
It'll get colder once the sun sets.
I should build a fire here.
But that'll fill the room with smoke.
Maybe I can leave it just outside the door.
I tried doing everything
I could think of to help.
And I figured it wasn't good for a human
to be around, so I left them alone.
I hope I didn't end up bothering them
by trying to help too much.
If that giant boar attacked while she was
giving birth and unable to move...
It might be because of the light
from the fire next to the hut,
but everything else
looks really dark tonight.
Oh no, I fell asleep!
Uh, I'm coming in.
They look calm now that it's all over.
But I'm sure she had a really tough night.
Oh yeah.
To celebrate her giving birth, I cut up
the tastiest looking parts from the boar.
I thought the dogs would go off somewhere
after she gave birth, but...
it looks like they're going to
hang around here.
Since it seems like they're
really attached to that hut,
I can't bring myself to kick them out.
So I built myself a new house.
I'd like to think I've improved
since the first home that I built.
By the time the puppies were
old enough to start running around,
the plants were big enough for me
to start harvesting them.
These are tomatoes.
Left alone, they grew into a tangled mess.
They're pretty hard to harvest,
and they look kind of small.
But they're definitely tomatoes!
The dogs do some hunting
and protect the premises for me.
By the way, it's getting tricky
just calling them all "dogs",
Kuro (black)
Yuki (snow)
so I decided to give them names.
The boy is Kuro. The girl is Yuki.
Kuro (black)
Yuki (snow)
Kuroone
Kurotwo
Kurothree
Kurofour
She's got dark fur too, though.
Kuro. Yuki.
I didn't think dogs would eat vegetables,
but seeing them enjoying
the vegetables so much
makes me want to work harder to grow
better vegetables to feed them.
I've been pretty busy with
harvesting vegetables,
which makes me want to shout with joy.
I'll need to build a storehouse for them.
I want to build furniture and tools, too.
There's a lot of stuff I want to do.
Well, there's no rush.
I'll take my time working at it.
Well
Fence and ditch
Hut 1
Hut 2
Toilet
Vegetable fields
You want to cross the mountain?
Listen miss, unless you're drunk,
you really shouldn't be saying stuff like that.
Haven't you heard of The Forest of Death?
That's what's on the other side of the mountain.
It's full of dangerous monsters.
If any of them ever came down here
and attacked us,
the town would need guards on duty 24/7.
That might be just what I'm looking for.
Next time
Episode 2
The First Villager